M. Arif Hilman Al Muhtadin, S.Psi, CHRP

Organization Development & Talent Management Specialist +62 813 8190 1911 | arif.elmuhtadin@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/arifelmuhtadin

SUMMARY

A Human Resources professional with a specialty in organizational development & talent management areas. Well experienced in Organizational Design, Job Analysis, Job Evaluation, Designing Competency, Business Process Design & Improvement, Performance management, Career Management and Talent Management. The most important thing about my job is supporting my stakeholders to achieve their goals align with HR perspective, company vision & culture.

SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

- Organization Design
- Talent & Career Management
- Performance Management
- Succession Planning
- Job Analysis & Job Evaluation
- Data Analytic
- HR Policy
- Employee Survey

WORK EXPERIENCES

Jul 2022 - Now

Organization Development Specialist & Sales HRBP - PT. Delisari Nusantara

Responsible for organization structure & design, workforce planning, job descriptions, performance appraisal, competency management, talent management, organization diagnostic & intervention, employee survey, and career management to create and maintain high performing organizations.

Major Responsibilities:

- Identify organization issues from the aspect of culture, people behaviors, & business processes.
- Conduct the Talent Mapping.
- Review the sales policies, processes, rewards and recognition schemes
- Act as a point of contact for both employees (especially for Sales Dept.) and management
- Providing coaching and feedback method for manager on how they can improve their team' s performance
- Analyze issue related to employees and performance in organization
- Monitor employee & sales productivity and create improvement performance plan

Jan 2022 – Jun 2022

Assistant Manager HR System & Policy - Citra Borneo Indah Group

Responsible in creating organization structure & design, workforce planning, HR Policy, job descriptions, performance planning, competency matrix & dictionary, and HR Information System

Major accomplishments:

- Design HR Policies & Procedures for holding Company (Promotion Procedures, Transfers & Rotations, Talent Management Procedures, Employee Benefits, Training & Development Procedures, New Employee On Boarding Procedures, Performance Management Procedures)
- Develop methods for creating and cascading Company KPIs to the individual level
- Develop HRIS Framework and design as a reference for the IT Developer team to develop HRIS
- Create New Competency Dictionary

Nov 2020 – Dec 2021

Assistant Manager Organization Development - Citra Borneo Indah Group

Responsible for organization structure & design, workforce planning, HR Policy, job descriptions, performance appraisal, competency management, talent management, organization diagnostic &

intervention, employee survey, and career management to create and maintain high performing organizations.

Major responsibilities & accomplishments:

- Design Career Path based on job family movement
- Develop methods for creating and cascading Company KPIs to the individual level
- Create an outline for a Leadership Development Program to prepare future leaders of the holding company.
- Develop a talent management & succession planning framework, policy & procedure
- Develop a talent development program based on Human Asset Value (nine boxes) & competency gap
- Provide guidelines and facilitate user in creating key performance indicator
- Analyzing business structures, procedures, processes, and the utilization of resources.
- Deliver recommendation of effective solutions to meet business challenges and mitigate business risks from Organization strategy

Apr 2019 – Oct 2020

HR Planning Staff - PT. Nindya Karya (Persero)

Working collaboratively with HR Planning Manager to create organizational design, man power planning, job descriptions, performance appraisal, talent management, and career management align with business strategy

Major accomplishments:

- Develop Integrated Talent & Career Management System
- · Provide guidelines in creating Man Power Planning Based on predicted number & type of projects
- Provide guidelines and facilitate user in creating key performance indicator.
- Provide guidelines to conduct work load analysis.
- Develop HR policies and procedures
- Remapping business process & redesign organization based on remapping result

May 2017 - Sep 2018

Organizational Development Staff - PT. Cakrawala Andalas Televisi, Tbk (ANTV)

Working collaboratively with OD Supervisor in creating organizational structure & design, workforce planning, job descriptions, performance management processes, and monitor the process of mutation, promotion and placement of employees to create and maintain effectiveness of organization.

Major Responsibilities:

- · Perform administrative and monitoring processes on employee promotion, mutation and rotation
- Develop, design, implement and monitor Performance Management system.
- Create matrix competency models
- Conduct job analysis and workload analysis
- · Conduct the Talent Mapping process
- Develop career path models and job grading.
- Design new Performance Management System by implement real time performance review

Achievement:

- Win the HC Technology Competition from SWA Magazine (2017)
- Win Employers of Choice Awards (EOC) from SWA Magazine (2017)

Mar 2016 – Jan 2017 | HR Generalist - PT. St. Morita Industries

As an individual contributor responsible for the day-to-day of human resources operations tasks in every area of HR, including recruiting, compensation and benefits, employee training and industrial relation.

Major Responsibilities:

- Implement and administer employee data
- Responsible in talent acquisition and recruitment processes
- Develop, design, implement and monitor Performance Management system.
- Develop, design, implement and monitor Training & Development program.
- Responsible in administering employee compensation & benefit program.

Jan 2015 - Jan 2016

Admin Psychotest – PT. Sarlito Bina Persona (Biro Psikologi Sarlito & Rekan)

Responsible for the entire psychotest process from preparation, giving test instructions, administration, and scoring.

Psychological test used:

- IQ = APM / SPM, CFIT, IST, TIU I-V
- Personality: EPPS, Papikostick, DISC, Graphic (DAP, BAUM, WZT)
- Creativity: verbal test, numerical tests.
- Others: MSDT (Management Style Diagnostic Test), Kreaplin, Pauli.

SPEAKER EXPERIENCE

Dec - Apr 2022

Basic HR Development Program - A2S Consulting

Module:

- 1. Basic HR
- 2. Job Analysis & Job Evaluation
- 3. Performance Management
- 4. Competency Management
- 5. Talent Management
- 6. Training & Development

Sep 2020

Millennials Online Career Fair – Degree Fair HMD Pertanian UNDIP

Aug 2020 May 2020 Career Course Module Excelling at The Job Interview – Outstanding Youth Indonesia

BCTalk Module Basic HR For Fresh Graduates – HRD Bacot

EDUCATION

2009 - 2015

Bachelor of Psychology | *Islamic State University Syarif Hidayatullah Jakarta* with GPA 3.27.

CERTIFICATION

2020

2020

Certified Human Resource Professional (CHRP) | UNIKA Atmajaya

TRAINING & COURSE

2022	People Analytics for Strategic HR, Sailendra Institute
2021	People Analytics, Algorit.ma
2021	Corporate Strategic Planning And Organizational Agility, Airlangga Executive Education Center
2021	Advanced Human Capital Accomplish, UNIKA Atmajaya
2021	Certified Organization Development Associate (CODA) Module Strategic Planning, Transforma
	Consulting
2020	Basic Human Resource Professional (Dasar & Lanjut), One CHRP
2020	Perancangan Struktur Organisasi Berbasis Proses Bisnis, IHRI
2020	How to Create HR Budget, One CHRP
2020	HR Score Card & HR Activity Plan, One CHRP
2020	Performance Management Systems, IHRI

Job Evaluation in Making Job Grading, Pungki Purnadi & Associates